{"eras": [{"preamble": "Welcome to Palestine! You said goodbye to your family in their village in Tsarist Russia. After a sea voyage, you disembark in the port city of Haifa. The dry, hilly landscape looks alien to your eyes. \n\nYou arrive with a loaf of bread, a small purse of currency, and a dog-eared copy of Old New Land\u2014Theodor Herzl's vision of a new state for the scattered and oppressed Jewish people. You left your home to fulfill his dream here in Palestine. \n\nThe Turkish customs agent demands to see your visa. You show him the creased paperwork and he clears you for entry. You wander through the streets and souks of Haifa. Arab pedlars mind shops and show off their wares. The forested heights of Mt. Carmel rise from the Mediterranean shoreline and the hectic activity of the port. In cafes and hostels, you meet newly arrived Jewish pioneers\u2014-young idealists like yourself\u2014and debate work prospects and the vision of settling this land.\n\nThe next day, you visit the Palestine Office and present a letter of introduction to the administrator.", "postamble": "You journey first to a training farm outside of Haifa, operated by the Palestine Office, where learn how to care for animals and till the land. For a year, you work in the city's port during the day to raise money and plan your future with new comrades from your youth movement. Together, you will work as a collective and vote on all decisions as a group. \n\nYou will live as absolute equals. You will build a village. You will found a nation You will heal the world.\n\nFinally, you receive official news of your next destination.... and begin the journey to a new frontier.", "questions": [{"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": 0, "sol": 5, "econ": -5, "answer": "Marxist"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Socialist"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": -5, "econ": 5, "answer": "Labor Zionist"}, {"rep": -5, "pop": 5, "sol": 5, "econ": 0, "answer": "Religious"}], "question": "What youth movement did you belong to?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": -2, "sol": 0, "econ": -10, "answer": "North"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "East"}, {"rep": -5, "pop": 2, "sol": 0, "econ": 5, "answer": "South"}], "question": "Where in Palestine do you want to settle?"}]}, {"preamble": "Founding of Kibbutz: 1910-1918", "postamble": "", "questions": [{"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": 2, "sol": -2, "econ": 5, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": -1, "econ": 2, "answer": "Training Farm"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": -2, "sol": 0, "econ": -2, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Can Miriam learn cattle-raising from Arab farmer?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": 3, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Parents"}, {"rep": 5, "pop": -3, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Kibbutz"}], "question": "Who names child?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": -5, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": 2, "answer": "No"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 3, "sol": 0, "econ": 5, "answer": "Rent"}], "question": "Do you return fields to Arab farmers?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 2, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "Coordination"}, {"rep": 5, "pop": -3, "sol": 2, "econ": -2, "answer": "Defense"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": 5, "sol": 0, "econ": -2, "answer": "Illegal immigration"}], "question": "How do you respond to immigration limits?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": -1, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "Remove"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 1, "sol": -2, "econ": 1, "answer": "Forgive"}], "question": "What do you do about lazy member?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 2, "pop": -1, "sol": 2, "econ": -2, "answer": "Retaliate"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": -1, "econ": 2, "answer": "Ignore"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": 2, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Militia"}], "question": "How do you respond to ambush?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": -2, "sol": -2, "econ": 2, "answer": "Remove"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Ignore"}, {"rep": 5, "pop": 0, "sol": 5, "econ": -2, "answer": "Listen"}], "question": "What do you do about the philosopher?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -5, "pop": -1, "sol": 1, "econ": 0, "answer": "Remove"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "Advise"}, {"rep": 5, "pop": 1, "sol": -1, "econ": 2, "answer": "Ignore"}], "question": "What do you do about the fancy American?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -2, "pop": -1, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Remove"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": -3, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Retain"}], "question": "What do you do about the poetess with TB?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": -2, "sol": -2, "econ": -5, "answer": "Stay"}, {"rep": -10, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 5, "answer": "Relocate"}, {"rep": -2, "pop": 2, "sol": 0, "econ": 2, "answer": "Lease"}], "question": "What do you do about poor fields?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": 0, "sol": -2, "econ": 5, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Do you join co-op?"}]}, {"preamble": "British Mandate & Arab Uprising: 1919-1936", "postamble": "", "questions": [{"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": -3, "sol": 0, "econ": -2, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 2, "sol": 0, "econ": 2, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Do you fight with the veteran?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -5, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": 2, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 3, "pop": -2, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Do you relocate because of suicides?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 2, "pop": 1, "sol": -2, "econ": -2, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": -1, "sol": 2, "econ": 2, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Do you accept the novelist?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 0, "pop": -5, "sol": 0, "econ": -1, "answer": "Leave"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": 0, "sol": 2, "econ": 0, "answer": "Stay"}], "question": "What do you tell  Soviet sympathizers?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -2, "pop": 0, "sol": -2, "econ": 5, "answer": "Hire Arabs"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 2, "sol": -1, "econ": 3, "answer": "Hire Jews"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": 0, "sol": 1, "econ": 1, "answer": "No hire"}], "question": "How do you harvest bounty crop?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": 5, "pop": -15, "sol": 5, "econ": -2, "answer": "Split"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 15, "sol": -5, "econ": 5, "answer": "Faster"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 5, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "Status quo"}], "question": "How should you grow?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -2, "pop": 4, "sol": -2, "econ": 5, "answer": "Yes"}, {"rep": 2, "pop": -1, "sol": 0, "econ": 0, "answer": "No"}], "question": "Can members work outside kibbutz?"}, {"answers": [{"rep": -2, "pop": 0, "sol": 0, "econ": 2, "answer": "Hire help"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 1, "sol": 2, "econ": 2, "answer": "Other kibbutz"}, {"rep": 0, "pop": 2, "sol": 2, "econ": -2, "answer": "Delay"}], "question": "How do you drain swamp?"}]}]}